<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@cullaloe | Tech, tales and imagery</title>
    <description>@cullaloe</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 12:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 12:09:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting started with remote teaching</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended an online CPD session today, run by Michael Gallagher for staff moving rapidly and unexpectedly to online teaching during the COVID-19 virus outbreak. Jon Jack operated the back channel chat room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continuity-contact-care&quot;&gt;Continuity, contact, care&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael opened with a presentation to frame the session, beginning with the intention of moving teaching online in this emergency situation. He reminded us of the availability of local support for technical matters and discipline-focused matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continuity-contact-care-1&quot;&gt;Continuity, contact, care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These three are the core concepts to think about when moving to online teaching in these circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuity means our duty to provide students with some teaching provision. Putting material on to the VLE is a start, and also some live sessions to provide synchronous teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact is important through regular announcements and communications, probably weekly, and active participation in discussion boards. These actions will reduce social distancing which is a bad thing. It is important to be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care is providing the right support for students and making sure that all are engaged. Self-care for the teaching staff is also important - there is no need to be online 24/7, nor even out of working hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outline&quot;&gt;Outline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a critical element of online (and all good) teaching, which I recognise as the “Road Map” I have been talking to my students about as a key feature of teaching. Michael’s suggested outline structure for teaching online is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Objective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Readings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lecture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synchronous event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Questions for discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weekly announcement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support is a good idea, too, including having someone to manage the back channel in online synchronous sessions. It’s hard to manage live delivery and the chat room at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q--a&quot;&gt;Q &amp;amp; A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some useful tips and queries came out of the Q &amp;amp; A after Michael’s presentation, including my own, which was if the bandwidth is rubbish, I have used collaborate with a phone call for 1-1 tutorials with students - the whiteboard and app sharing are really useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evaluation-and-next-steps&quot;&gt;Evaluation and next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a really useful session to help me think about the delivery of teaching and support of my students in coming weeks of isolation. I’ll be carrying these ideas and tips into my planning for next week (once I get this marking done).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/remote-teaching/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/remote-teaching/</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RPS Distinction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Royal Photographic Society has recommended a panel of my photographs for the distinction of Licentiate (LRPS). This, some 8 months after my wife and I first submitted, with one of us being awarded LRPS immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-lrps-panel&quot;&gt;The LRPS Panel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//live.staticflickr.com/65535/47090178004_03b333d55c_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to make changes to one of my images (09 Fenchurch Street) to remove distracting lines that were at first taken to be a printing error. You can see all of the images in the panel over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/gp/mrhood/G74Mv4&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;panel-layout&quot;&gt;Panel Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//live.staticflickr.com/65535/34002450088_aae778fc84_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes called the eleventh image, the layout of the panel of photographs is an important aspect for the assessors. There has to be a pleasing aesthetic to the arrangement and balance of the images when displayed as a complete body. I spent far too long worrying about details of aspect ratio and colour balance across the panel, I think. The advisory day was useful to get a sense of what the assessors like. These are things like the two faces looking inwards, similar colours at each end of a row, those kinds of spectrumy details that provide satisfaction for a critical viewer, and they are, critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/RPS_LRPS_RGB.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;RPS Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to have finally achieved this distinction which I take to be an acknowledgement that I am learning something about photography. I’d like to continue my artistic journey by developing my knowledge and skills of the photographic process. I have continued this through making the improvements required to the panel first submitted, and by exploring composition using medium format film, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Film/ISO&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Header image&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;16mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;03 Julian Alps, one of the images in my LRPS Panel.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;09 Fenchurch Street&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fuji X-E2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fujifilm Fujinon XF27mm F2.8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1/450s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;The image not up to standard first time, with the lines visible.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/lrps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/lrps/</guid>
        
        <category>Imagery</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capture One Webinar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Capture One is the preferred choice of many photographers, me included. One reason for this is that Phase One, the company behind the program, understand excellence in design, production and performance and that these depend on effective learning by the users of their products. To this end, they operate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.captureone.com/&quot;&gt;learning hub&lt;/a&gt;. With the recent release of a new version, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.captureone.com/&quot;&gt;Capture One Pro 20&lt;/a&gt;, new webinars and tutorials allow users to get the most from the new developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accessed two of these, the first a recording of a webinar &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.captureone.com/webinars/top-5-things-to-know-about-capture-one-20/&quot;&gt;Top 5 things to know about Capture One Pro 20&lt;/a&gt;, and the second, through live participation in a webinar &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.captureone.com/webinars/new-to-capture-one-hit-the-ground-running/&quot;&gt;Hit the Ground Running&lt;/a&gt;, designed for new users to the software. Although I have been using Capture One for a year or so now, this seminar was useful to get me familiar with the new features and a more professional workflow. I went on to access some of the short tutorials in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.captureone.com/&quot;&gt;Learning Hub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capture One Pro is a powerful digital photography management and editing software program made by the Danish manufacturers of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phaseone.com/&quot;&gt;Phase One&lt;/a&gt; cameras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Poppies” image © 2019. A quick re-edit using the new program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/capture-one-webinar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/capture-one-webinar/</guid>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        <category>Photography</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Backing up a VPS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly back up the files on my VPS&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I do this using a script run from the terminal on any convenient machine, usually a MacBook laptop. This is the script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-d&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/VPS_rsync &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;mkdir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-p&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/VPS_rsync
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/VPS_rsync
rsync &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-avz&lt;/span&gt; user@server.tld:/path/to/vhosts/ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; VPS_rsync.date
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line tells OSX that what follows is a bash script and should run in the Bourne Again Shell (bash). Next, a folder is created in the current user’s download directory, which is then made the current working directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rsync command is then issued with a username and the name of the server to be backed up - in this case &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;server.tld&lt;/code&gt;, and the directory on the server to be backed up. I am backing up the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;vhosts&lt;/code&gt; directory which contains all of the files and folders that my VPS serves. The dot at the end of that line tells &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; to download the data to the current directory. The server will issue a login challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last line of the script prints the current timestamp to a file. Once complete (it can take a while) the files can be relocated to an offline storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Server. A rented computer that contains, manages and serves websites and other services on the Internet. Mine is in London. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/backup-a-vps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/backup-a-vps/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IT Futures Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The theme of the 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itfutures.ed.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;IT Futures Conference&lt;/a&gt; was “Automating our future: opportunities and threats.” It was opened by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/principals-office/principal-biography&quot;&gt;Prof. Peter Mathieson&lt;/a&gt;, who put a positive and hopeful spin on what for some may have been a depressing morning after the election that returned Boris Johnson a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conservativehome.com/video/2019/12/listen-a-huge-great-stonking-mandate-the-prime-ministers-victory-speech-at-cchq.html&quot;&gt;huge great stonking mandate&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Principal’s expectation that the university would have a significant role to play in the unfolding future was underpinned by much of what followed in the rest of the day. He noted that removal of uncertainty is good and that technology holds the key in, e.g. modernisation of online learning and the curriculum. He cited Edinburgh’s credentials in AI&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Ed1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Ed1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and spoke about the donation made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bailliegifford.com/&quot;&gt;Baillie Gifford&lt;/a&gt; in supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://efi.ed.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Edinburgh Futures Institute&lt;/a&gt;, which offers such opportunity to the city, the University and the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;morning-sessions&quot;&gt;Morning sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science fiction writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipope.org/charlie/&quot;&gt;Charlie Stross&lt;/a&gt; read us his wittily titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2019/12/artificial-intelligence-threat.html&quot;&gt;prepared talk&lt;/a&gt;, “Artificial Intelligence: Threat or Menace?” which was lightweight, lightly entertaining&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:charlie&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:charlie&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and entirely inconsequential in comparison with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Bundy&quot;&gt;Alan Bundy&lt;/a&gt;’s excellent “brief history” of AI which was very well pitched for the audience and delivered the forecast that the future of AI is in hybrid systems. Alan included specific acknowledgement of Turing’s 1950 work, &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:at1950&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:at1950&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; one of my all-time favourite papers, which I now have on my Christmas reading list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project on automated subtitling was presented by two of the officers involved. They concluded that such efforts in inclusion and accessibility should involve students, not least because of the employment opportunity such activity presents but also because the students are more effective than the automated process alone - another example of hybrid solutions in the application of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.research.ed.ac.uk/portal/en/persons/jane-hillston(b223964a-b6ef-4ca3-a6f4-8d8eca420a49).html&quot;&gt;Professor Jane Hillston&lt;/a&gt;, head of the School of Informatics, spoke to us on the theme of “AI for good”. Her talk included plans for a centre of that name. Speaking on data ethics, Jane referenced the short film &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CO6M2HsoIA&quot;&gt;Slaughterbots&lt;/a&gt; as one vision of the application of AI:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CO6M2HsoIA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randall Munroe’s vision is no less concerning &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1968/&quot;&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/robot_future.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found Jane’s talk to take a distinct political tone, as academic leaders do sometimes when justifying their positions and the funding they require, but I must not be cynical about this because as a society, we certainly do need a voice to advocate for the responsible application of AI and her new centre might just be that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;afternoon-sessions&quot;&gt;Afternoon sessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a networking lunch, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inf.ed.ac.uk/people/staff/Yakov_Gal.html&quot;&gt;Kobi Gal&lt;/a&gt; presented similar messages to those he presented at a seminar I attended in February, namely that students online don’t like participating in forums, and that collaborative tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notabene.com/&quot;&gt;Nota Bene&lt;/a&gt; can go some way to mitigating that problem. I found myself disappointed in this talk for the same reasons I was disappointed in February: despite this being presented as an example of modern and well-funded research, it still is a manifestly amateur and ill-informed effort that “betrays a gap in understanding of pedagogy that could easily be addressed through dialogue with educators.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:feb2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:feb2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I am personally surprised, knowing what outstanding work is being done in and around AI, that this work is sustainable. One of my former PhD supervisors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/profile/hamish-macleod&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamish MacLeod&lt;/a&gt; took the role of “discussant” and asked some interesting questions that avoided critique of Kobi’s talk, instead focusing on some important general matters such as the limitations of AI for identifying the “teachable moment”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:hamish1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:hamish1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and the danger of what Hamish called “the tyranny of the majority” in which the needs of the individual learner are ignored&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tweet2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tweet2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Law School’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.ed.ac.uk/people/professor-burkhard-schafer&quot;&gt;Burkhard Schafer&lt;/a&gt; told a story of how a German police response to legitimate protest was exposed through a paper trail that revealed how they had taken decisions and actions that were in effect, oppression of civil rights. Burkhard’s warning for citizen-state interaction is that AI will not leave such a trace and so cannot be monitored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/security_question.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can you imagine this implemented in deep networks?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/565/&quot;&gt;XKCD again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.de.ed.ac.uk/people/dr-michael-gallagher&quot;&gt;Michael Gallagher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.de.ed.ac.uk/people/dr-markus-breines&quot;&gt;Markus Breines&lt;/a&gt; presented initial findings from their research in the use of automated agents in teaching which focused more on automation of workflow and processes than machine learning. They make use of several automated agents such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cullaloe.net/w/index.php?title=Teacherbot:_Can_Robot_Teachers_Do_It_Better%3F&quot;&gt;TeacherBot&lt;/a&gt; and are asking questions about what the teacher function is. These researchers seem to right on the money with their work, as they seem to understand the pedagogical and social implcations of their work, citing the Chinese social credit&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:chinasc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:chinasc&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; innovation as an example of what’s happening in the world with automation systems, and drawing on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.ed.ac.uk/manifestoteachingonline/the-text/&quot;&gt;2016 Manifesto for Teaching Online&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration[plan]. I can hardly do justice to the excitement I felt in this talk and the restoration of my faith in high quality academic work being done here at Edinburgh. If you have ideas for them to look at in their study, they are open to suggestions at &lt;a href=&quot;//bit.ly/edteacher&quot;&gt;bit.ly/edteacher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final presentation of the day was as exciting and uplifting as anything I could have asked for today. It was given by the new DDI boss, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/news/staff/2018/data-driven-innovation-lead-announced&quot;&gt;Jarmo Eskelinen&lt;/a&gt;, who gave us an update and details on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ddi.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;DDI&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acceleratinggrowth.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Edinburgh City Deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University’s CIO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/principals-office/vice-principals-senior-leadership/senior-leadership-team/mclachlan&quot;&gt;Gavin McLachlan&lt;/a&gt;, closed the conference with his summary of the day, suggesting that we may be entering a new Scottish Enlightenment, which is perhaps a little hyperbolic but is an understandable claim, given Jarmo’s intentions for DDI of making Edinburgh the “Data Capital of Europe (only Europe doesn’t know it yet)”. From what I’ve seen at other recent events, we’re already on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Ed1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Edinburgh was the second University in the world to offer a course in AI, after Stanford. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Ed1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:charlie&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The tweetable quote from Charlie’s talk was, “&lt;em&gt;Emergent culture does not have to make sense&lt;/em&gt;.” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:charlie&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:at1950&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Turing, A. M. (1950) ‘Computing Machinery and Intelligence’, Mind. Oxford University Press, LIX(236), pp. 433–460. doi: 10.1093/mind/LIX.236.433. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:at1950&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:feb2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;From my notes on Kobi’s February seminar formerly &lt;a href=&quot;https://cullaloe.net/w/index.php?title=Development_diary_2019#RSASmartCities&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; but now offline. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:feb2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:hamish1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;see Havinghurst, R. J. (1952) Human Development and Education, p.5. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:hamish1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:tweet2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Kobi’s tweetable quote: “… you can’t be an ex-physicist. It’s like a religion.” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tweet2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:chinasc&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/china-social-credit-system-explained&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; for example, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/china-experiments-with-sweeping-social-credit-system/a-42030727&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; for background and commentary. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:chinasc&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/futures-conference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/futures-conference/</guid>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSERC Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sserc.org.uk/&quot;&gt;SSERC&lt;/a&gt; Annual Science &amp;amp; Technology Conference was held this year at the Carnegie Conference Centre in the old capital, Dunfermline. I took the opportunity to attend as an antidote to the intensity of recent weeks on the road visiting schools, and was particularly keen to refresh my ideas for practical physics in the classroom. I was not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome-and-keynotes&quot;&gt;Welcome and Keynotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alastair MacGregor, SSERC’s CEO, opened the conference with an optimistic sketch of how the organisation is developing in the coming months and years, focusing on the emerging partnerships, ventures and refreshing of channels &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:one&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:one&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Proper acknowledgement was made of the work of well-kent faces at SSERC&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:PB&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:PB&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were keynote talks given by Graeme McAlister of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childminding.org/&quot;&gt;Scottish Childminding Association&lt;/a&gt; and Howie Firth of &lt;a href=&quot;http://oisf.org/&quot;&gt;Orkney Science Festival&lt;/a&gt;, and a briefing on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sserc.org.uk/wider-engagement/the-young-stem-leader-programme/&quot;&gt;Young STEM Leader&lt;/a&gt; programme from Graeme Young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources-to-support-the-sciences&quot;&gt;Resources to support the sciences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coffee, a carousel of wokshops showcasing ideas and resources designed to support teaching of the three sciences in secondary schools. The physics workshop, titled, “Micro:Bit Magic” and led by Gregor Steele and Norman Bethune, was of particular interest and relevance to me, although the others were no less full of great ideas and advice for teachers and technicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the physics session, there was the usual torture of a Teddy Bear&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:teddy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:teddy&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, in the name of science. Resources on display included holographic CD cases that use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://holhocollection.com/&quot;&gt;HOLHO&lt;/a&gt; animations on an iPad or phone to display 3-D moving graphics; microscale vacuum kit; a Canadian $5 bill with a holographic security device; thermochromic film and electro Lycra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch and a Health and Safety update, I returned to the physics team and another workshop, this time focusing on support for the senior phase. We conducted a quick investigation into the charging of a capacitor, plotting a nice curve, as an example of core experiments in this phase. An activity&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:norm&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:norm&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that I will most certainly follow up on with my students is the investigation of the resistance of various lengths and widths of a conducting material used to make anti-static bags, and the making of capacitors using the same material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;networking&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is always good to catch up with friends and colleagues at events like these, and this was no exception. A week after this conference, I saw many of them again in the pub nearest to SSERC in Rosyth for a farewell “pie and a pint” with Paul Beaumont who retires soon. It was especially nice to see Jim Jamieson, Gregor’s predecessor in Physics and Radiation Protection in Scotland, at this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:one&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For example, the rebranding of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8ZyrUqeupcWKVNXYPgTohA&quot;&gt;SSERC TV&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:one&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:PB&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Paul Beaumont in particular, who is retiring. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:PB&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:teddy&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The bear was fitted with an accelerometer and Micro:Bit, programmed to detect falls. Teddy is test pilot for a device with a nice social justice dimension. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:teddy&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:norm&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I agreed with Norman, whose idea this was, that I will wait until after the SUSS conference in January before introducing the activity to my PGDE students. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:norm&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/SSERC-conference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/SSERC-conference/</guid>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deploying a Jekyll site from GitHub</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been building a site using Jekyll and hosting the code on GitHub. The site is available on GitHub pages from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; folder in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;branch, but I wanted to deploy it to a server running Centos and Apache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the VPS, from behind the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;httpdocs&lt;/code&gt; or web-facing folder, clone the GitHub repository into a new folder (in his example, both the repository and the local folder are called “foobar”):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git clone https://github.com/githubuser/foobar.git foobar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to serve the site files from the docs folder in the repository. Include this in the Apache/Nginx configuration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-apache highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Alias&lt;/span&gt; /foobar /var/www/vhosts/thesite/foobar/docs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updating the site just requires &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ git pull&lt;/code&gt; from the repository folder on the web server. Depending on how you are logged in to the server, you may need to change the folder permissions so Apache can serve the pages and find the css, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/deploy-jekyll-site-from-github/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/deploy-jekyll-site-from-github/</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IDL Planning Meeting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geos.ed.ac.uk/homes/cgraham/&quot;&gt;Professor Colin Graham&lt;/a&gt; has been driving recent initiatives in the development of interdisciplinary learning (IDL). He organised a gathering of interested people at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rse.org.uk/&quot;&gt;RSE&lt;/a&gt; to consider the establishment of an IDL Forum whereby practitioners could share ideas and have a conversation about how to implement IDL in schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was privileged to have been invited in part because of my involvement in initial teacher education at Edinburgh, but also because I have experience in setting up and operating professional community spaces in education&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:sptr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:sptr&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After introductions, Colin outlined the scope of support being made available by the RSE in bringing people together to progress the IDL forum. The elements needed were articulated as a platform, and people to moderate it. Scott Bryce&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:SB&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:SB&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; shared his perspective of the establishment of science teacher networks in Scotland, stressing the need for a few moderators to volunteer from the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/profile/stuart-nicol&quot;&gt;Stuart Nicol&lt;/a&gt; talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.ed.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Open Education Resources (OER)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;TES Connect&lt;/a&gt; for resource storage, and the requirement to use open licences like &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt; in these spaces. As well as advising on matters like turnover of people in running facilities such as are proposed, Stuart identified the three elements of what is being aimed for: a &lt;strong&gt;front end&lt;/strong&gt; or web interface for users; &lt;strong&gt;resources&lt;/strong&gt; storage and curation; and a &lt;strong&gt;forum&lt;/strong&gt; space for dialogue and support for the community. These three need not be connected to each other except through hyperlinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the meeting discussed questions around IDL and what it is; examples of good practice&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ddb&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ddb&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; and some of the expectations that might be met in bringing together practitioners in IDL to support each other, share ideas and promote wider implementation of interdisciplinary teaching and learning in our schools. I have agreed to continue to be involved with this project and advise where I can. First actions seem to be establishment of the forum and getting a discussion going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-idl-forum&quot;&gt;The IDL Forum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up the IDL forum after meeting with Stuart and Colin in December. We settled on the University of Edinburgh’s Mailing List Service which operates using a hybrid suite based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sympa.com/&quot;&gt;Sympa&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://mlist.is.ed.ac.uk/lists/arc/idled&quot;&gt;List archive&lt;/a&gt; is public. At the end of 2019, we are setting up a pilot group to poke at the forum and seed a discussion or two, with perhaps a more open launch early in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:sptr&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://networkedprofessionals.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/sputnik-to-pixies-an-example-of-an-online-professional-community/&quot;&gt;SPTR&lt;/a&gt; for physics teachers. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:sptr&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:SB&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;SYNAPSE and STRONTIUM are the networks for Biology and Chemistry teachers in Scotland, established by Scott. He acknowledged, once prompted, that these came on the back of and with support from sptr, SPUTNIK and the physics community, which had established communities since 2004. SYNAPSE and STRONTIUM make use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Groups&lt;/a&gt; for forums and &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/&quot;&gt;GDrive&lt;/a&gt; for resources storage, with the attendant problems of Local Authority filtering and data security. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:SB&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ddb&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://daydreambelievers.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Daydream Believers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ddb&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/IDL-planning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/IDL-planning/</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OSX Finder stuck in loop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I keep quite a lot of folders on my desktop - keeping the current work in view, and offloading completed projects rather than have them hanging about my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the Mac OSX desktop can be sensitive to what’s on the desktop, which can cause the Finder app to get itself in a loop of locking up (wheel of death) and then crashing (or forced relaunch), only to repeat the cycle. This is frustrating for the user. Restarting the computer does not solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A way to exit this is to move all of the desktop files to a new temporary location:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo mkdir&lt;/span&gt; /Users/username/Documents/tempfolder
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo mv&lt;/span&gt; /Users/username/Desktop/&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; /Users/username/Documents/tempfolder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; should be replaced with the affected account’s username. This can be done from another logged in user’s account but I was able to perform these commands from my usual account. Having restarted to allow Finder to get over its crisis, I was able to move them back again (drag ‘n’ drop) and delete the temporary folder without the problem recurring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo rm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-rf&lt;/span&gt; tempfolder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a useful thread with more details on possible causes over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hints.macworld.com/article.php?story=20060308010111601&quot;&gt;MacWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 08:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/osx-finder-stuck-in-loop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/osx-finder-stuck-in-loop/</guid>
        
        <category>OSX</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to stop Chrome fetching localhost over https</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whilst developing Jekyll sites locally, the Chrome browser will sometimes try to fetch the page over &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;, rather than &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http&lt;/code&gt;. This is problematic, because the browser just renders a protocol error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chrome-https.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is caused by a security policy &lt;strong&gt;HSTS&lt;/strong&gt;, or HTTP Strict Transport Security. We have to tell Chrome to forget that it wants to fetch localhost over a secure connection. To do this, visit &lt;a href=&quot;chrome://net-internals/#hsts&quot;&gt;chrome://net-internals/#hsts&lt;/a&gt; and find the field called &lt;strong&gt;Delete domain security policies&lt;/strong&gt;. Enter &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;localhost:4000&lt;/code&gt; (or whatever address you are using for the local jekyll server) and click delete. Chrome will now fetch the site over http again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, I am grateful to the responses over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/25277457/google-chrome-redirecting-localhost-to-https&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;. If this doesn’t fix your problem then that’s the next place you should look.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 20:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chrome-force-localhost-http/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chrome-force-localhost-http/</guid>
        
        <category>Chrome</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
