<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@cullaloe | Tech, tales and imagery</title>
    <description>@cullaloe</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/sitemap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 23:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 23:06:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting started with remote teaching</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended an online CPD session today, run by Michael Gallagher for staff moving rapidly and unexpectedly to online teaching during the COVID-19 virus outbreak. Jon Jack operated the back channel chat room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continuity-contact-care&quot;&gt;Continuity, contact, care&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael opened with a presentation to frame the session, beginning with the intention of moving teaching online in this emergency situation. He reminded us of the availability of local support for technical matters and discipline-focused matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continuity-contact-care-1&quot;&gt;Continuity, contact, care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These three are the core concepts to think about when moving to online teaching in these circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuity means our duty to provide students with some teaching provision. Putting material on to the VLE is a start, and also some live sessions to provide synchronous teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact is important through regular announcements and communications, probably weekly, and active participation in discussion boards. These actions will reduce social distancing which is a bad thing. It is important to be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care is providing the right support for students and making sure that all are engaged. Self-care for the teaching staff is also important - there is no need to be online 24/7, nor even out of working hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outline&quot;&gt;Outline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a critical element of online (and all good) teaching, which I recognise as the “Road Map” I have been talking to my students about as a key feature of teaching. Michael’s suggested outline structure for teaching online is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Objective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Readings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lecture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synchronous event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Questions for discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weekly announcement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support is a good idea, too, including having someone to manage the back channel in online synchronous sessions. It’s hard to manage live delivery and the chat room at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;q--a&quot;&gt;Q &amp;amp; A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some useful tips and queries came out of the Q &amp;amp; A after Michael’s presentation, including my own, which was if the bandwidth is rubbish, I have used collaborate with a phone call for 1-1 tutorials with students - the whiteboard and app sharing are really useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evaluation-and-next-steps&quot;&gt;Evaluation and next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a really useful session to help me think about the delivery of teaching and support of my students in coming weeks of isolation. I’ll be carrying these ideas and tips into my planning for next week (once I get this marking done).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/remote-teaching/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/remote-teaching/</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RPS Distinction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Royal Photographic Society has recommended a panel of my photographs for the distinction of Licentiate (LRPS). This, some 8 months after my wife and I first submitted, with one of us being awarded LRPS immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-lrps-panel&quot;&gt;The LRPS Panel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//live.staticflickr.com/65535/47090178004_03b333d55c_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to make changes to one of my images (09 Fenchurch Street) to remove distracting lines that were at first taken to be a printing error. You can see all of the images in the panel over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/gp/mrhood/G74Mv4&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;panel-layout&quot;&gt;Panel Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//live.staticflickr.com/65535/34002450088_aae778fc84_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes called the eleventh image, the layout of the panel of photographs is an important aspect for the assessors. There has to be a pleasing aesthetic to the arrangement and balance of the images when displayed as a complete body. I spent far too long worrying about details of aspect ratio and colour balance across the panel, I think. The advisory day was useful to get a sense of what the assessors like. These are things like the two faces looking inwards, similar colours at each end of a row, those kinds of spectrumy details that provide satisfaction for a critical viewer, and they are, critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/RPS_LRPS_RGB.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;RPS Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to have finally achieved this distinction which I take to be an acknowledgement that I am learning something about photography. I’d like to continue my artistic journey by developing my knowledge and skills of the photographic process. I have continued this through making the improvements required to the panel first submitted, and by exploring composition using medium format film, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Film/ISO&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Header image&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;16mm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;03 Julian Alps, one of the images in my LRPS Panel.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;09 Fenchurch Street&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fuji X-E2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fujifilm Fujinon XF27mm F2.8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1/450s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;The image not up to standard first time, with the lines visible.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/lrps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/lrps/</guid>
        
        <category>Imagery</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Backing up a VPS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly back up the files on my VPS&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I do this using a script run from the terminal on any convenient machine, usually a MacBook laptop. This is the script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-d&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/VPS_rsync &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;mkdir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-p&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/VPS_rsync
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~/Downloads/VPS_rsync
rsync &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-avz&lt;/span&gt; user@server.tld:/path/to/vhosts/ &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; VPS_rsync.date
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line tells OSX that what follows is a bash script and should run in the Bourne Again Shell (bash). Next, a folder is created in the current user’s download directory, which is then made the current working directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rsync command is then issued with a username and the name of the server to be backed up - in this case &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;server.tld&lt;/code&gt;, and the directory on the server to be backed up. I am backing up the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;vhosts&lt;/code&gt; directory which contains all of the files and folders that my VPS serves. The dot at the end of that line tells &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; to download the data to the current directory. The server will issue a login challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last line of the script prints the current timestamp to a file. Once complete (it can take a while) the files can be relocated to an offline storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Server. A rented computer that contains, manages and serves websites and other services on the Internet. Mine is in London. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/backup-a-vps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/backup-a-vps/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IT Futures Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The theme of the 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itfutures.ed.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;IT Futures Conference&lt;/a&gt; was “Automating our future: opportunities and threats.” It was opened by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/principals-office/principal-biography&quot;&gt;Prof. Peter Mathieson&lt;/a&gt;, who put a positive and hopeful spin on what for some may have been a depressing morning after the election that returned Boris Johnson a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conservativehome.com/video/2019/12/listen-a-huge-great-stonking-mandate-the-prime-ministers-victory-speech-at-cchq.html&quot;&gt;huge great stonking mandate&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Principal’s expectation that the university would have a significant role to play in the unfolding future was underpinned by much of what followed in the rest of the day. He noted that removal of uncertainty is good and that technology holds the key in, e.g. modernisation of online learning and the curriculum. He cited Edinburgh’s credentials in AI&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Ed1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Ed1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and spoke about the donation made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bailliegifford.com/&quot;&gt;Baillie Gifford&lt;/a&gt; in supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://efi.ed.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Edinburgh Futures Institute&lt;/a&gt;, which offers such opportunity to the city, the University and the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;morning-sessions&quot;&gt;Morning sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science fiction writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipope.org/charlie/&quot;&gt;Charlie Stross&lt;/a&gt; read us his wittily titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2019/12/artificial-intelligence-threat.html&quot;&gt;prepared talk&lt;/a&gt;, “Artificial Intelligence: Threat or Menace?” which was lightweight, lightly entertaining&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:charlie&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:charlie&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and entirely inconsequential in comparison with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Bundy&quot;&gt;Alan Bundy&lt;/a&gt;’s excellent “brief history” of AI which was very well pitched for the audience and delivered the forecast that the future of AI is in hybrid systems. Alan included specific acknowledgement of Turing’s 1950 work, &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:at1950&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:at1950&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; one of my all-time favourite papers, which I now have on my Christmas reading list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project on automated subtitling was presented by two of the officers involved. They concluded that such efforts in inclusion and accessibility should involve students, not least because of the employment opportunity such activity presents but also because the students are more effective than the automated process alone - another example of hybrid solutions in the application of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.research.ed.ac.uk/portal/en/persons/jane-hillston(b223964a-b6ef-4ca3-a6f4-8d8eca420a49).html&quot;&gt;Professor Jane Hillston&lt;/a&gt;, head of the School of Informatics, spoke to us on the theme of “AI for good”. Her talk included plans for a centre of that name. Speaking on data ethics, Jane referenced the short film &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CO6M2HsoIA&quot;&gt;Slaughterbots&lt;/a&gt; as one vision of the application of AI:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CO6M2HsoIA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randall Munroe’s vision is no less concerning &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1968/&quot;&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/robot_future.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found Jane’s talk to take a distinct political tone, as academic leaders do sometimes when justifying their positions and the funding they require, but I must not be cynical about this because as a society, we certainly do need a voice to advocate for the responsible application of AI and her new centre might just be that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;afternoon-sessions&quot;&gt;Afternoon sessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a networking lunch, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inf.ed.ac.uk/people/staff/Yakov_Gal.html&quot;&gt;Kobi Gal&lt;/a&gt; presented similar messages to those he presented at a seminar I attended in February, namely that students online don’t like participating in forums, and that collaborative tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notabene.com/&quot;&gt;Nota Bene&lt;/a&gt; can go some way to mitigating that problem. I found myself disappointed in this talk for the same reasons I was disappointed in February: despite this being presented as an example of modern and well-funded research, it still is a manifestly amateur and ill-informed effort that “betrays a gap in understanding of pedagogy that could easily be addressed through dialogue with educators.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:feb2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:feb2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I am personally surprised, knowing what outstanding work is being done in and around AI, that this work is sustainable. One of my former PhD supervisors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/profile/hamish-macleod&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamish MacLeod&lt;/a&gt; took the role of “discussant” and asked some interesting questions that avoided critique of Kobi’s talk, instead focusing on some important general matters such as the limitations of AI for identifying the “teachable moment”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:hamish1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:hamish1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and the danger of what Hamish called “the tyranny of the majority” in which the needs of the individual learner are ignored&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:tweet2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:tweet2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Law School’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.ed.ac.uk/people/professor-burkhard-schafer&quot;&gt;Burkhard Schafer&lt;/a&gt; told a story of how a German police response to legitimate protest was exposed through a paper trail that revealed how they had taken decisions and actions that were in effect, oppression of civil rights. Burkhard’s warning for citizen-state interaction is that AI will not leave such a trace and so cannot be monitored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/security_question.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can you imagine this implemented in deep networks?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/565/&quot;&gt;XKCD again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.de.ed.ac.uk/people/dr-michael-gallagher&quot;&gt;Michael Gallagher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.de.ed.ac.uk/people/dr-markus-breines&quot;&gt;Markus Breines&lt;/a&gt; presented initial findings from their research in the use of automated agents in teaching which focused more on automation of workflow and processes than machine learning. They make use of several automated agents such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cullaloe.net/w/index.php?title=Teacherbot:_Can_Robot_Teachers_Do_It_Better%3F&quot;&gt;TeacherBot&lt;/a&gt; and are asking questions about what the teacher function is. These researchers seem to right on the money with their work, as they seem to understand the pedagogical and social implcations of their work, citing the Chinese social credit&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:chinasc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:chinasc&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; innovation as an example of what’s happening in the world with automation systems, and drawing on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.ed.ac.uk/manifestoteachingonline/the-text/&quot;&gt;2016 Manifesto for Teaching Online&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration[plan]. I can hardly do justice to the excitement I felt in this talk and the restoration of my faith in high quality academic work being done here at Edinburgh. If you have ideas for them to look at in their study, they are open to suggestions at &lt;a href=&quot;//bit.ly/edteacher&quot;&gt;bit.ly/edteacher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final presentation of the day was as exciting and uplifting as anything I could have asked for today. It was given by the new DDI boss, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/news/staff/2018/data-driven-innovation-lead-announced&quot;&gt;Jarmo Eskelinen&lt;/a&gt;, who gave us an update and details on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ddi.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;DDI&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acceleratinggrowth.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Edinburgh City Deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University’s CIO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/principals-office/vice-principals-senior-leadership/senior-leadership-team/mclachlan&quot;&gt;Gavin McLachlan&lt;/a&gt;, closed the conference with his summary of the day, suggesting that we may be entering a new Scottish Enlightenment, which is perhaps a little hyperbolic but is an understandable claim, given Jarmo’s intentions for DDI of making Edinburgh the “Data Capital of Europe (only Europe doesn’t know it yet)”. From what I’ve seen at other recent events, we’re already on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Ed1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Edinburgh was the second University in the world to offer a course in AI, after Stanford. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Ed1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:charlie&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The tweetable quote from Charlie’s talk was, “&lt;em&gt;Emergent culture does not have to make sense&lt;/em&gt;.” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:charlie&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:at1950&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Turing, A. M. (1950) ‘Computing Machinery and Intelligence’, Mind. Oxford University Press, LIX(236), pp. 433–460. doi: 10.1093/mind/LIX.236.433. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:at1950&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:feb2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;From my notes on Kobi’s February seminar formerly &lt;a href=&quot;https://cullaloe.net/w/index.php?title=Development_diary_2019#RSASmartCities&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; but now offline. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:feb2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:hamish1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;see Havinghurst, R. J. (1952) Human Development and Education, p.5. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:hamish1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:tweet2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Kobi’s tweetable quote: “… you can’t be an ex-physicist. It’s like a religion.” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:tweet2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:chinasc&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/china-social-credit-system-explained&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; for example, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/china-experiments-with-sweeping-social-credit-system/a-42030727&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; for background and commentary. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:chinasc&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/futures-conference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/futures-conference/</guid>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSERC Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sserc.org.uk/&quot;&gt;SSERC&lt;/a&gt; Annual Science &amp;amp; Technology Conference was held this year at the Carnegie Conference Centre in the old capital, Dunfermline. I took the opportunity to attend as an antidote to the intensity of recent weeks on the road visiting schools, and was particularly keen to refresh my ideas for practical physics in the classroom. I was not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome-and-keynotes&quot;&gt;Welcome and Keynotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alastair MacGregor, SSERC’s CEO, opened the conference with an optimistic sketch of how the organisation is developing in the coming months and years, focusing on the emerging partnerships, ventures and refreshing of channels &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:one&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:one&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Proper acknowledgement was made of the work of well-kent faces at SSERC&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:PB&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:PB&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were keynote talks given by Graeme McAlister of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childminding.org/&quot;&gt;Scottish Childminding Association&lt;/a&gt; and Howie Firth of &lt;a href=&quot;http://oisf.org/&quot;&gt;Orkney Science Festival&lt;/a&gt;, and a briefing on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sserc.org.uk/wider-engagement/the-young-stem-leader-programme/&quot;&gt;Young STEM Leader&lt;/a&gt; programme from Graeme Young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources-to-support-the-sciences&quot;&gt;Resources to support the sciences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coffee, a carousel of wokshops showcasing ideas and resources designed to support teaching of the three sciences in secondary schools. The physics workshop, titled, “Micro:Bit Magic” and led by Gregor Steele and Norman Bethune, was of particular interest and relevance to me, although the others were no less full of great ideas and advice for teachers and technicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the physics session, there was the usual torture of a Teddy Bear&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:teddy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:teddy&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, in the name of science. Resources on display included holographic CD cases that use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://holhocollection.com/&quot;&gt;HOLHO&lt;/a&gt; animations on an iPad or phone to display 3-D moving graphics; microscale vacuum kit; a Canadian $5 bill with a holographic security device; thermochromic film and electro Lycra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch and a Health and Safety update, I returned to the physics team and another workshop, this time focusing on support for the senior phase. We conducted a quick investigation into the charging of a capacitor, plotting a nice curve, as an example of core experiments in this phase. An activity&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:norm&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:norm&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that I will most certainly follow up on with my students is the investigation of the resistance of various lengths and widths of a conducting material used to make anti-static bags, and the making of capacitors using the same material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;networking&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is always good to catch up with friends and colleagues at events like these, and this was no exception. A week after this conference, I saw many of them again in the pub nearest to SSERC in Rosyth for a farewell “pie and a pint” with Paul Beaumont who retires soon. It was especially nice to see Jim Jamieson, Gregor’s predecessor in Physics and Radiation Protection in Scotland, at this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:one&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For example, the rebranding of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8ZyrUqeupcWKVNXYPgTohA&quot;&gt;SSERC TV&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:one&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:PB&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Paul Beaumont in particular, who is retiring. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:PB&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:teddy&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The bear was fitted with an accelerometer and Micro:Bit, programmed to detect falls. Teddy is test pilot for a device with a nice social justice dimension. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:teddy&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:norm&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I agreed with Norman, whose idea this was, that I will wait until after the SUSS conference in January before introducing the activity to my PGDE students. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:norm&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/SSERC-conference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/SSERC-conference/</guid>
        
        <category>CPD</category>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deploying a Jekyll site from GitHub</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been building a site using Jekyll and hosting the code on GitHub. The site is available on GitHub pages from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; folder in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;branch, but I wanted to deploy it to a server running Centos and Apache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the VPS, from behind the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;httpdocs&lt;/code&gt; or web-facing folder, clone the GitHub repository into a new folder (in his example, both the repository and the local folder are called “foobar”):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git clone https://github.com/githubuser/foobar.git foobar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to serve the site files from the docs folder in the repository. Include this in the Apache/Nginx configuration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-apache highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Alias&lt;/span&gt; /foobar /var/www/vhosts/thesite/foobar/docs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updating the site just requires &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ git pull&lt;/code&gt; from the repository folder on the web server. Depending on how you are logged in to the server, you may need to change the folder permissions so Apache can serve the pages and find the css, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/deploy-jekyll-site-from-github/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/deploy-jekyll-site-from-github/</guid>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OSX Finder stuck in loop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I keep quite a lot of folders on my desktop - keeping the current work in view, and offloading completed projects rather than have them hanging about my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the Mac OSX desktop can be sensitive to what’s on the desktop, which can cause the Finder app to get itself in a loop of locking up (wheel of death) and then crashing (or forced relaunch), only to repeat the cycle. This is frustrating for the user. Restarting the computer does not solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A way to exit this is to move all of the desktop files to a new temporary location:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo mkdir&lt;/span&gt; /Users/username/Documents/tempfolder
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo mv&lt;/span&gt; /Users/username/Desktop/&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; /Users/username/Documents/tempfolder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; should be replaced with the affected account’s username. This can be done from another logged in user’s account but I was able to perform these commands from my usual account. Having restarted to allow Finder to get over its crisis, I was able to move them back again (drag ‘n’ drop) and delete the temporary folder without the problem recurring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo rm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-rf&lt;/span&gt; tempfolder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a useful thread with more details on possible causes over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hints.macworld.com/article.php?story=20060308010111601&quot;&gt;MacWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 08:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/osx-finder-stuck-in-loop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/osx-finder-stuck-in-loop/</guid>
        
        <category>OSX</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to stop Chrome fetching localhost over https</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whilst developing Jekyll sites locally, the Chrome browser will sometimes try to fetch the page over &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;, rather than &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http&lt;/code&gt;. This is problematic, because the browser just renders a protocol error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chrome-https.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is caused by a security policy &lt;strong&gt;HSTS&lt;/strong&gt;, or HTTP Strict Transport Security. We have to tell Chrome to forget that it wants to fetch localhost over a secure connection. To do this, visit &lt;a href=&quot;chrome://net-internals/#hsts&quot;&gt;chrome://net-internals/#hsts&lt;/a&gt; and find the field called &lt;strong&gt;Delete domain security policies&lt;/strong&gt;. Enter &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;localhost:4000&lt;/code&gt; (or whatever address you are using for the local jekyll server) and click delete. Chrome will now fetch the site over http again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, I am grateful to the responses over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/25277457/google-chrome-redirecting-localhost-to-https&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;. If this doesn’t fix your problem then that’s the next place you should look.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 20:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chrome-force-localhost-http/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chrome-force-localhost-http/</guid>
        
        <category>Chrome</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Invalid active developer path after upgrade to Catalana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After allowing my MacBook Air to upgrade itself to OSX 10.15 Catalana, git commands throw an error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git status
xcrun: error: invalid active developer path &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;/Library/Developer/CommandLineTools&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;, missing xcrun at: /Library/Developer/CommandLineTools/usr/bin/xcrun
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because OSX updates remove the developer tools. You need to re-install them (and agree the license again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;xcode-select &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--install&lt;/span&gt;
xcode-select: note: &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;requested &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;command &lt;/span&gt;line developer tools
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to the contributors on &lt;a href=&quot;https://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/254380/why-am-i-getting-an-invalid-active-developer-path-when-attempting-to-use-git-a&quot;&gt;Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt; for the solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 14:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/invalid-active-developer-path/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/invalid-active-developer-path/</guid>
        
        <category>OSX</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Presentations in Markdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have needed a way to make a quick presentation that does not require the use of huge complex programs like PowerPoint or KeyNote. One way I have been using recently is to write the outline in markdown (as I would when sketching out a lesson plan) and then using the amazing pandoc to magic up a pdf. Here are the key elements of your markdown file and how to produce one for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yaml-header&quot;&gt;YAML Header&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;title: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;author: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Hood&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;date: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;22nd September 2019&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;classoption: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;aspectratio=169&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-presentation&quot;&gt;The presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slide heading level is determined by the first heading that is followed by content. Any headings above that will be treated as section header slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any references can be automatically expanded into a list at the end of the final slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Bullets and links

* First [Link](https://cullaloe.net)!
* No link
* Bullet

# Q &amp;amp; A

## References
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-make-the-presentation&quot;&gt;How to make the presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;pandoc &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-t&lt;/span&gt; beamer Example.md &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; Example.pdf &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--bibliography&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/path/to/bibliography.bib&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-V theme:Pittsburgh&lt;/code&gt; for non-default themes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-V colortheme:beaver&lt;/code&gt; for non-default colours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-V fonttheme:structuresmallcapsserif&lt;/code&gt; for non-default fonts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Themes, etc. are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deic.uab.es/~iblanes/beamer_gallery/index_by_theme.html&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-i-need-a-powerpoint&quot;&gt;But I need a PowerPoint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you really have to, change the output format from pdf to pptx and remove &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-t beamer&lt;/code&gt; from the command. The output is a bit funky, but will give you a starting point for editing and formatting in PowerPoint if that’s what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 13:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/presentation-in-markdown/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/presentation-in-markdown/</guid>
        
        <category>Markdown</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arch Linux on OSX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve wanted to take a look at Arch Linux for a while now, and when a student got me to connect her inherited Arch laptop to the University Wi-Fi network last week, I was reminded that this lightweight distribution is attractive to the increasingly paranoid control freak that I am becoming. Having toyed with the idea of spending money on an XPS or some other super-cool hacker machine, and having been defeated by prudence, here’s how I got it running as a first-time-out instance on my University MacBook Air&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Mac&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Mac&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-host&quot;&gt;The Host&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I really can’t justify a separate development machine, especially as I have use of a decent spec laptop. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/download/&quot;&gt;Arch download page&lt;/a&gt; includes a number of different ways of acquiring the distro, including using &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.vagrantup.com/archlinux/boxes/archlinux&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; with VirtualBox, which I had intended to plug an Arch ISO disk into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-virtual-machine&quot;&gt;The Virtual Machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded and installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vagrantup.com/&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; and gave it a spin with the example Ubuntu 12.04 LTS. Installation, running and logging in to the instance takes three commands…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;vagrant init hashicorp/precise64
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;vagrant up
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;vagrant ssh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arch&quot;&gt;Arch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firing up Arch itself could be done the same way, but the Vagrant site hints that once Vagrant is installed on your dev machine, all you need is a Vagrantfile with the right info in it. Here’s the MWE&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:MWE&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:MWE&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I started with. It uses ruby syntax, and was simply a new directory containing a single file called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Vagrantfile&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;configure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;vm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;box&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;archlinux/archlinux&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a super quick and easy way to get Arch up and running. Now, you just type the command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;vagrant up
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will download and install a fresh instance of Arch and fire it up, ready for you to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Mac&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;MacBook Air specs: 13-inch, Early 2015, 2.2 GHz Intel Core i7, 8GB DDR. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Mac&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:MWE&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Minimum working example. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:MWE&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/arch-linux-on-osx/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/arch-linux-on-osx/</guid>
        
        <category>OSX</category>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Connecting to eduroam on Arch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Students on Initial Teacher Education programmes are beginning their studies this week. One of the students asked me to help get her connected to the eduroam academic wireless network. She had got the technical people in the library to look at it and they had got it going by doing some voodoo with a USB stick, but the connection would not re-establish later in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voodoo was to provide a root Certificate file, downloadable from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed.ac.uk/information-services/computing/desktop-personal/wifi-networking/wlan-root-ca&quot;&gt;University&lt;/a&gt;, but the wireless configuration app had not imported the certificate as the tech person had evidently assumed it would do. All I had to do was copy the certificate to the student’s laptop (an old Acer) and configure the network connection to point to the new location of the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laptop had had its old Windows OS replaced by the student’s dad by Arch Linux. Not my first choice for a day to day operating system but the student’s dad had done a great job in setting it up with all the apps she needed, and apart from the wireless connection, everything was working sweetly. A classic case for a cheap and sustainable computing solution!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/connecting-to-eduroam-arch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/connecting-to-eduroam-arch/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PhD Workflow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been setting up document repositories and workflows for a potential new research project which will consider teaching approaches for the understanding of complex ideas. In the project, there will be criticism of social constructivism as a default pedagogy and examination of intelligent automation of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;workflow&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools-and-software&quot;&gt;Tools and software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents will be retained in a GitHub private repository, and written in markdown either using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://macdown.uranusjr.com/&quot;&gt;OSX MacDown app&lt;/a&gt; or the cross-platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/&quot;&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt;. Masters will be kept in pdf, converted using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jgm/pandoc-citeproc&quot;&gt;pandoc-citeproc&lt;/a&gt; taking care of linking to bibliographies. These will be produced and managed using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mendeley.com&quot;&gt;Mendeley&lt;/a&gt;, which itself serves as a multi-device reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-the-documents&quot;&gt;Making the documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the documents are in markdown, with a YAML header containing information about it. You can make pdf, docx, or html versions of these documents in one of two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Visual Studio, with appropriate settings, using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dfinke/vscode-pandoc&quot;&gt;vscode-pandoc&lt;/a&gt; extension. Issue the command by pressing cmd-K, then P. Select the format you need. pdf is default, so hit return.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the command line, in the source folder, type:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;pandoc filename.md &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; filename.pdf &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--bibliography&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/path/to/Bibliographies/PhD.bib&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-research-project&quot;&gt;The research project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2014 and 2016 I engaged in a PhD project that was looking at &lt;strong&gt;the characteristics of the transaction space between teacher and learner in traditional and technology enhanced education.&lt;/strong&gt; The idea for this came about from the use of a modified form of the traditional Cambridge Tutorial method and developed to consider teaching spaces that are characterised by the absence of the teacher such as the MOOC. The project didn’t get to data gathering before it was abandoned for lack of time and funds to continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;early-ideas&quot;&gt;Early ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early stages of this revisit, I wanted to look at this space as being mediated by some graphical image as stimulus for deep, disruptive, and enriching learning. The space may be adversarial, and is is designed to be social and creative. This approach is applied where the learning relates to understanding of some known topic of a complex nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;development&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of July 2019, I have rejected these ideas as I begin to recognize that perhaps that which I peddle is Snake Oil, or at least, not without serious faults. This is not to say that I reject the importance of the social dimension in certain learning spaces, just that it is neither necessary nor sufficient for learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/phd-workflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/phd-workflow/</guid>
        
        <category>Markdown</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Error</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My normally quiescent twitter feed lit up a little this week in a case of mistaken identity, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/googleanalytics&quot;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; posted about Scroll Depth Heat Maps in Google’s Data studio. Google tagged me instead of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://datarunsdeep.com.au/who-we-are#nick-hood&quot;&gt;Data Analyst, Nick Hood&lt;/a&gt; who wrote the blog post they were reporting on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was particularly funny about this was a response from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BoilingSky&quot;&gt;Dave Jackson&lt;/a&gt; that “Scroll depth … has ruined vast areas of the internet”, the responsibility for which I quickly claimed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All good clean banter, and dealt with appropriately by the other Nick Hood, who waved at me, internet-style, from his data business in Australia. Hello back, Nick. Thanks for the reminder that there are people in the world who aren’t constantly looking for others to make faces at, or blame for their misery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if you think that I am responsible for ruining vast areas of the internet, yeah, I did that. You can get my cv &lt;a href=&quot;https://cullaloe.com/cv.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you want to offer me a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/IMG_8123-sm.png&quot; alt=&quot;screen grab&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/IMG_8124.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;screen grab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/data-error/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/data-error/</guid>
        
        <category>Analytics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NextCloud update to 15.0.8</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxunplugged.com/307&quot;&gt;Linux Unplugged 307&lt;/a&gt;, which featured a discussion on NextCloud and its various features, prompted me to check the software state of my own instance running on my VPS&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:VPS&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:VPS&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logging in to the admin interface, it was easy enough to update to the latest version 15.0.8, automatically. I took a look at some of the apps mentioned in the podcast: I am using calendar, contacts, email and files on a daily basis, all fully integrated with my (mostly Mac-based) business workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not tempted much by the notes app because the OSX- and IOS-based email notes work very well on all of my devices except Linux machines. This isn’t a problem, but wouldn’t it be nice to have a fully device agnostic notes solution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openweathermap.org/&quot;&gt;OpenWeather&lt;/a&gt; API app was quick and easy to set up within the dashboard. I now know when it’s raining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:VPS&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Server &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:VPS&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 15:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nextcloud-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nextcloud-update/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technical Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am bringing together my posts on coding, technical matters and things related to my online services like the VPS that hosts the various websites I operate. These had previously sat within my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://cullaloe.com&quot;&gt;personal blog&lt;/a&gt; along with commentary on education, reviews, rants, and photographs of cats (&lt;a href=&quot;https://500px.com/photo/272137057/take-me-home-by-nick-hood&quot;&gt;I kid you not&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new blog, hosted on GitHub pages, will be the home of my technical blog. I am in the process of migrating articles from the old WordPress site into the cleaner markdown used within the jekyll static page environment here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get in touch, by all means use the channel links in the sidebar, or add a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 15:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/technical-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/technical-blog/</guid>
        
        <category>Media</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Problem Occurred. The web page couldn’t be loaded.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This message appears in the pop-up dialog when trying to connect to new (mostly public) wifi routers using MacOS Mojave 10.14. I’ve been resorting to using my phone’s personal hotspot but this is no good when there is a poor mobile signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fix is to cancel the dialog, open a browser and navigate to &lt;a href=&quot;http://captive.apple.com&quot;&gt;http://captive.apple.com&lt;/a&gt;. This forces the browser to open the captive login/service page (perhaps after a refresh), allowing a connection to the local wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to connect to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonvpn.com/&quot;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-problem-occurred-the-web-page-couldnt-be-loaded/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-problem-occurred-the-web-page-couldnt-be-loaded/</guid>
        
        <category>OSX</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wordpress editor stuck in code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The new Wordpress editor, Gutenberg, has had a mixed reception. For users that are only occasional editors on a site, it can be a pain to get to grips with, especially as the implementation is still quite buggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my clients tried to add a post to a site he hadn’t contributed to for some time and ran straight into a difficulty: the visual editor wasn’t working for him at all. His view should have been this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screenshot-2019-02-14-at-16.06.03.png&quot; alt=&quot;should&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…but what he got instead was this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screenshot-2019-02-14-at-16.07.36.png&quot; alt=&quot;did&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, his interface was stuck in the code editor. Unfortunately, he had no way of changing this (and neither did I as admin) in the UI. We changed a lot of variables, suspecting first his browser choice (Edge) and then OS choice (Windows). Long story short, the fix is to add an entry into the user’s meta table setting the rich_editing variable true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sql highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;INSERT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;INTO&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;`wp_usermeta`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;`umeta_id`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;`user_id`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;`meta_key`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;`meta_value`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;VALUES&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'999'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'rich_editing'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'true'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 15:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wordpress-editor-stuck-in-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wordpress-editor-stuck-in-code/</guid>
        
        <category>WordPress</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rename Image Files in Folders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a Python script to walk a directory tree, renaming .jpg and .JPG files. It was written for a client who had a directory containing multiple directories, each containing zero or more (up to 100) image files. Most of the images were named &amp;lt;abitrary name 1&amp;gt;.jpg or &amp;lt;arbitrary name 2&amp;gt;.JPG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client wanted each folder’s images to be numbered 001.jpg to nnn.jpg for some further process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-py highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;imghdr&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;renamefiles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rootstructure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;abspath&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dirs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;walk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rootstructure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getcwd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Reset the counter
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;chdir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;imghdr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'jpeg'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;zfill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Specify the full path to the directory here.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;renamefiles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/Users/myuser/Desktop/TheImageFolder&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pre&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 10:27:57 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/rename-image-files-in-folders/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rename-image-files-in-folders/</guid>
        
        <category>Python</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grav Error 403 in Admin Panel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m trying out &lt;a href=&quot;https://getgrav.org/&quot;&gt;Grav&lt;/a&gt;, a flat file CMS, on my server. It looks promising, having just &lt;a href=&quot;https://photo.cullaloe.net/&quot;&gt;installed it&lt;/a&gt; with the admin plugin. It seems that there is a fairly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/getgrav/grav-plugin-admin/issues/979&quot;&gt;well-known problem&lt;/a&gt; with false positives from apache’s mod security web application firewall software, which manifests as an annoying 403 error banner in the admin pages (and the notifications panel not loading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is easily fixed by whitelisting &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.atomicorp.com/wiki/index.php/WAF_350147&quot;&gt;mod security rule 350147&lt;/a&gt;. In Plesk, mod security rules can be whitelisted in the &lt;strong&gt;Server Management&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Tools and Settings&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Web Application Firewall (ModSecurity)&lt;/strong&gt; page. Enter the security rule ID (in this case 350147) in the box at the end of the page and click apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a security risk associated with this and users should assess the risk to their servers before implementing this workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 10:15:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/grav-error-403-in-admin-panel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/grav-error-403-in-admin-panel/</guid>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Upgrading solr server from 6.6.0 to 7.3.1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use Apache’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://lucene.apache.org/solr/&quot;&gt;Solr&lt;/a&gt; to provide a global search facility on Moodle. Now that my courses have ended for the summer, it’s time to bite the bullet and upgrade the Solr server software from version 6.6.0 which I installed last year, to the current 7.3.1. This turned out to be more straightforward than I feared, and did not require me to touch the PHP solr module that I had to compile from source when I installed it the first time. Here are the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /opt
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;wget http://apache.mirrors.nublue.co.uk/lucene/solr/7.3.1/solr-7.3.1.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;tar &lt;/span&gt;zxvf solr-7.3.1.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cp &lt;/span&gt;solr-7.3.1/bin/install_solr_service.sh &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;rm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-rf&lt;/span&gt; solr-7.3.1
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./install_solr_service.sh solr-7.3.1.tgz &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-f&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the -f flag which tells the script to upgrade an existing installation. The script stops the currently running instance, extracts the new code and starts the instance. A quick check of the admin interface on port 8983 shows the new code running OK, the cores intact, and the client service on Moodle nominal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; At present (June 2018) &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.moodle.org/35/en/Global_search#The_Solr_server&quot;&gt;Solr 7 is not supported on Moodle 35&lt;/a&gt;. The latest version of the Solr server that works with Moodle 35 is 6.6.4: the instructions above will install Solr 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want global search to work with Moodle 35, replace “7.3.1” with “6.6.4” and fetch the code using wget from the Apache archive at &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.apache.org/dist/lucene/solr/6.6.4/solr-6.6.4.tgz&quot;&gt;http://archive.apache.org/dist/lucene/solr/6.6.4/solr-6.6.4.tgz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 17:36:30 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/13/upgrading-solr-server-from-6-6-0-to-7-3-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/13/upgrading-solr-server-from-6-6-0-to-7-3-1/</guid>
        
        <category>Moodle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TV On Demand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, we thought we’d catch up on Channel 4’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.channel4.com/programmes/humans&quot;&gt;Humans&lt;/a&gt; with some popcorn. On with the Sky box and the telly and press the TV guide. Catch up. Here we go. Microwave is on. Sounds of corn popping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sky says we have to contact them because that channel isn’t free to view on demand on the downstairs telly. Weird. We can watch Channel 4 for free on the internet-connected upstairs telly OK, but we wanted to sit with our popcorn, now ready to eat, downstairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, no problem. XBox. There’s an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XBox says it won’t connect to the internet because it wants to do an update first. Sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update eventually installed and restarted and we can sign in and find the app. It needs installed. No problem. Popcorn almost finished now. App installs, but Channel 4 wants us to sign in. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t sign in, we don’t have an account. Why would we have an account for a free-to-air TV channel? It seems we have to visit their website first to create one. Uckfay offhay. Have you people never heard of GDPR?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popcorn finished. The moment has gone. Casualty it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring on the AI revolution! Technology is no threat to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 21:14:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tv-on-demand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tv-on-demand/</guid>
        
        <category>Media</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Research releases exoplanet discovery ML code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, Google Research released the AI code used in the discovery of two new exoplanets. &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.googleblog.com/2018/03/open-sourcing-hunt-for-exoplanets.html&quot;&gt;Their article&lt;/a&gt; includes an accessible intro to planet hunting and machine learning for those interested in either topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The associated paper is mostly about the AI but includes a good sense of just what real planetary research looks like and how far it’s come: &lt;em&gt;Shallue, C.J. &amp;amp; Vanderburg, A., 2017. Identifying Exoplanets with Deep Learning: A Five Planet Resonant Chain around Kepler-80 and an Eighth Planet around Kepler-90. The Astronomical Journal, 155(2), p.94&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an interview with Chris Shallue, the lead author on the paper on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twimlai.com/twiml-talk-117-discovering-exoplanets-deep-learning-chris-shallue/&quot;&gt;TWIMLAI podcast&lt;/a&gt; which makes interesting listening for anyone interested in machine learning, AI or exoplanetary research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 11:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/google-research-releases-exoplanet-discovery-ml-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/google-research-releases-exoplanet-discovery-ml-code/</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Badges Closed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, that was another massive waste of time. For all the hype and hope of having truly transportable awards for training and achievement, backed by Mozilla, no less, the current state of play is pretty disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running an online resource for some of my students using Moodle, and have been experimenting with badges for minor achievements to help them remain motivated in an unpressurised way, in what is otherwise a highly pressurised programme. Feedback from them has been that the badges are just a bit of fun, really, and not a significant feature of the course. However, talking to one of the students recently revealed that if the badges were to be publicly show-offable, such as on a LinkedIn profile, then they would add a new level of significance that might help them work just that little bit harder to earn these little digital stickers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enabling the backpack link within Moodle and trying it for myself (yes, I have awarded myself one of my own badges, for testing purposes obv), I discover that the whole open badges thing is now dead, having been abandoned by Mozilla. Simple issues such as having multiple email accounts within the backpack remain of no interest as the whole idea withers and dies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shame. This whole internet thing seemed like a good idea when it was new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 23:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/open-badges-closed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/open-badges-closed/</guid>
        
        <category>Moodle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Source 1, Microsoft 0 (own goal)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’m sitting down to work on some stuff for my job that is in a Microsoft file format, because that’s what the corporate world uses, when this message appears. I managed to sign in using my corporate id and their subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What ticks me off is that I have already bought and paid for this software. It makes me even more determined to move to open source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 16:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/open-source-1-microsoft-0-own-goal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/open-source-1-microsoft-0-own-goal/</guid>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>tryGit: it's the teach, not the tech.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked up a link to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeschool.com/courses/try-git&quot;&gt;free online course&lt;/a&gt; from a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxvoice.com/podcast-season-5-episode-17/&quot;&gt;Linux Voice&lt;/a&gt; podcast. I tried the course and wasn’t really impressed with it. The interface is nice, with an embedded virtual terminal to let you practice typing in the commands but the pedagogy is pretty weak. There’s nothing in the presentation that indicates that the designers understand how to construct understanding: all this lovely bit of code is doing is rehearsing a list of commands (and there’s even a click-once shortcut if you can’t be bothered actually typing). It’s more of a checklist than a course. It would be easy to turn it into a really effective bit of online learning with the addition of some better structure and graphics, and maybe a little assessment for learning. A shame, really, as it is clearly a loss leader to sell the Code School itself: I am in the market for some good quality online learning in their area, but I’m not likely to look any further at their catalogue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 21:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trygit-its-the-teach-not-the-tech/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trygit-its-the-teach-not-the-tech/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ownCloud installation on Centos 7</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For some time, I’ve wanted to have a calendaring tool independent of Google Calendar, which has become a central tool to my productivity and a source of concern as to how much data profiling results from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This afternoon, I installed the open source ownCloud file storage, calendar and contacts suite on my Centos VPS. It was a straightforward exercise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a subdomain on the server and switch it to use PHP 5.6. Add &lt;strong&gt;/dev/urandom&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;open_basedir&lt;/strong&gt; in php settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a data folder behind the web root, chowned to the web user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a MySQL database for the ownCloud service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the web root folder, get the software:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;curl -O https://download.owncloud.org/community/owncloud-10.0.3.tar.bz2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the MD5 hash, chown and extract. Copy the extracted files into the root folder&lt;br /&gt;
(be careful to include dotfiles, e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cp owncloud/* .&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cp owncloud/.* .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit the domain to configure the installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this server now provides is an independent calendar service, contacts, and secure file storage, at no additional cost and under my own secure control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 21:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/owncloud-installation-on-centos-7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/owncloud-installation-on-centos-7/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Global Search for Moodle on Centos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My students are using a Moodle VLE to access resources and teaching materials and it became evident that some kind of global search function would help them find things quickly, especially later in the programme when they come to write their assignments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running Moodle on a CentOS 7.3 virtual private server with Plesk Onyx. The server hosts several other sites running WordPress, bespoke PHP and some other bits and pieces including the usual mail services. Some of the containers require the OS-standard PHP5.4 but a recent upgrade to Moodle 3.3 required me to switch the container to PHP 7.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing Global Search was a little tricky because of the multiple PHP versions running on the server, but I eventually figured it out to these key steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-the-solr-server&quot;&gt;Install the Solr Server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /opt
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;wget http://apache.mirrors.nublue.co.uk/lucene/solr/6.6.0/solr-6.6.0.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;tar &lt;/span&gt;zxvf solr-6.6.0.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cp &lt;/span&gt;solr-6.6.0/bin/install_solr_service.sh &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;rm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-rf&lt;/span&gt; solr-6.6.0
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./install_solr_service.sh solr-6.6.0.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;chkconfig solr on
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;su - solr &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/opt/solr/bin/solr create_core -c moodle&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to visit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://your-domain.tld:8983&lt;/code&gt; to verify the Solr server is running OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secure-the-solr-server&quot;&gt;Secure the Solr Server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Solr is open to the world. You might want to secure it by adding this at the end of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/opt/solr/server/etc/webdefault.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-xml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;security-constraint&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;web-resource-collection&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;web-resource-name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Solr Administration&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/web-resource-name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;url-pattern&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;/*&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/url-pattern&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/web-resource-collection&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;auth-constraint&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;role-name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;solr-admin&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/role-name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/auth-constraint&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/security-constraint&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;login-config&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;auth-method&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;BASIC&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/auth-method&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;realm-name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Solr Administration&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/realm-name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/login-config&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a file in the same directory called realm.properties containing your chosen authentication details (matching the role above) in a single line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;admin: password, solr-admin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, add this just before the last line in jetty.xml in the same directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-xml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Call&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;addBean&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Arg&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;New&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;org.eclipse.jetty.security.HashLoginService&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Solr Administration&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/Set&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;config&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;SystemProperty&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;jetty.home&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;default=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;/etc/realm.properties&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/Set&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;Set&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;refreshInterval&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/Set&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/New&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/Arg&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/Call&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-the-php-solr-extension&quot;&gt;Install the PHP Solr Extension&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rpm &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Uvh&lt;/span&gt; https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/epel-release-latest-7.noarch.rpm
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rpm &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-Uvh&lt;/span&gt; https://mirror.webtatic.com/yum/el7/webtatic-release.rpm
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;yum &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;libxml2-devel pcre-devel libcurl-devel php70w-devel php70w-pear
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to build the extension using the right versions of phpize and php-config for your version of PHP, in my case, 7.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; /opt
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;curl &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-O&lt;/span&gt; https://pecl.php.net/get/solr-2.4.0.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;tar &lt;/span&gt;zxvf solr-2.4.0.tgz
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;solr-2.4.0/
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;../plesk/php/7.0/bin/phpize
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./configure &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--with-php-config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/opt/plesk/php/7.0/bin/php-config
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;make
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;make &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cp&lt;/span&gt; /opt/solr-2.4.0/modules/solr.so /opt/plesk/php/7.0/lib64/php/modules/
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;service httpd restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the Site administration / ▶︎ Plugins / ▶︎ Search / ▶︎ Manage global search page in your Moodle installation to configure, index and enable the Solr Search Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am impressed with how quickly this has been used and appreciated by the students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 15:54:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/global-search-for-moodle-on-centos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/global-search-for-moodle-on-centos/</guid>
        
        <category>Linux</category>
        
        <category>Moodle</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>get_iplayer broken, version 3.00 available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of us who make use of the amazing &lt;code&gt;get_iplayer&lt;/code&gt; program to obtain clips and other resources for classroom and other conveniences, it comes as a bit of a blow to find that in the past week or two, it has stopped working. Fortunately, there is a new version of the program available that with a little effort, gets the facility working again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/get-iplayer/get_iplayer/wiki/release300&quot;&gt;the release notes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The BBC removed all the XML-based data sources used by get_iplayer on 2017-04-26, breaking a lot of get_iplayer functionality. That functionality has been restored, but there are changes to be aware of - get_iplayer has not survived unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil Lewis and the team have (once again) done a fantastic job of quickly responding to changes in the way the BBC delivers its content. Many, many thanks to all the devs and hacks involved in this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, my advice to users is to read the release notes carefully. You may also hit issues installing the new dependencies including &lt;a href=&quot;http://mojolicious.org/&quot;&gt;Mojolicious&lt;/a&gt; and Perl as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cpan.org/&quot;&gt;cpan perl repository&lt;/a&gt;. Persevere, there is lots of useful advice out there. Finally, finally, the cache updates are much slower than before, although they are now only updated weekly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 07:50:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/get_iplayer-broken-version-3-00-available/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/get_iplayer-broken-version-3-00-available/</guid>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scholarly Open Access</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I kept a link to Beall’s list on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PhDResources/&quot;&gt;PhD Resources Reddit&lt;/a&gt; and received a comment that alerted me to the post (reposted below) which reported the take-down of this incredibly useful resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Science itself is under attack by those governments, corporations and gangsters who profit from ignorance: Beall did a great service by “outing” bogus and fake journals who increasingly have been undermining the robust verification and publication of hard science findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comment on the reddit post is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PhDResources/comments/5uxpzt/scholarly_open_access_critical_analysis_of/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and calls for a distributed response that is resilient to the challenges that cannot be sustained by one man in academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post-truth era is here, now. Objective enquiry is under attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Updating this post in 2019, I discover that Beall’s list is archived and sometimes updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://beallslist.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 10:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/scholarly-open-access/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/scholarly-open-access/</guid>
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Moray House Sundial</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, after a year in careful storage, the Sundial Memorial returned to a place of honour and inspiration in the newly re-designed quad in front of Old Moray House.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The memorial was made in 1998 to commemorate 150 years of teacher training and education here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It stands now to inspire teachers from all over the world, whether just beginning their journey as educators, enhancing it or returning to it, of one of the most powerful aspirations and consequences of being an effective and transformative teacher: &lt;em&gt;know yourself&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 12:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/12/08/the-moray-house-sundial/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/12/08/the-moray-house-sundial/</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speed Reading Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from a speed reading workshop at Moray House today: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cullaloe.net/w/index.php?title=Speed_Reading_Workshop&quot;&gt;http://cullaloe.net/w/index.php?title=Speed_Reading_Workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 13:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/22/speed-reading-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/22/speed-reading-workshop/</guid>
        
        <category>Education</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
